You've done very well so far, Fedorin.
到目前为止你做得非常好，Fedorin
It's nothing more than blackmail.
只是勒索而已，没什么
Blackmail? I have threatened you with nothing.
勒索？我没拿任何事情威胁你
No, but you would if I refused.
是没有，但如果我决绝的话你就会
Fedorin, I keep on telling you,
Fedorin，我一再告诉你
this is just a form of comprehensive insurance, hm?
这只是某种形式上的综合保险，嗯？
There's nothing for you to worry about.
你没有什么可担心的
My dear man, I've done nothing
but praise you ever since we first met.
我亲爱的伙计，自从我们初次见面，我对你就只有赞叹
I said you should be European Controller.
I said I would support you.
我说过你将是欧洲控制员，我说过我会支持你
You've found out things about me,
lies that would damage me.
你发现了我一些事情，一些会毁我的谎言
On the contrary, I am doing you a good turn.
恰恰相反，我正在做对你有利的事情
I am actually suppressing facts about you.
事实上我是在压制你那些事实
- Lies, I tell you!
- Lies... Truth... Who knows?
- 谎言，我跟你说！  - 谎言...真实...谁知道呢
But we wouldn't like to put him to the test, would we?
但我们并不喜欢拿他做测试，对不？
There.
给你
What's this?
这是什么？
Used in the right way, at the right time,
it can dictate your own future
用对了方法，用对了时间，它就能决定你自己的未来
and the future of Alexander Denes.
还有 Alexander Denes 的未来
Poison...
毒药...
I want you to take a message...
我要你带一个消息...
- McCrimmon! What are you doing dressed like this?
- Leader's orders.
- McCrimmon! 你穿成这样是要做什么？  - 领袖的命令
Now that you're here, I've got some questions to ask you.
既然你在这里，我有些问题要问你
I have better things to do, thank you.
我有重要的事情要做，谢谢你
I want to know what Salamander and Giles Kent were discussing
我想要知道 Salamander 和 Giles Kent 在讨论什么
- when I saw you last time?
- It's not for me to tell you that.
- 就我上次见到你的时候 - 这个不该我来告诉你
I am concerned of Salamander's safety.
我担心 Salamander 的安全
Giles Kent is Salamander's bitter enemy.
Giles Kent 是 Salamander 的死敌
If Salamander wishes you to know that,
I dare say he'll tell you himself.
如果 Salamander 想让你知道，我敢说他会自己告诉你的
You'll get no confidential items out of me.
你从我这里得不到机密信息
Listen. You must go away from here.
听着。你必须离开这里
Don't get caught up in Salamander's world.
别搅和到 Salamander 的世界里面
Why? What do you mean? You sound as if you don't like him.
为什么？你什么意思？听起来你好像不喜欢他
- Like him? I ...
- Hello there.
- 喜欢他？我  - 你好啊
Finish writing those menus.
把那些菜单写完
- Did you hear that?
- Aye. Work on her.
- 你听到了吗？  -  嗯，做她的工作
I have a feeling she can tell us something about Salamander.
我感觉她能告诉我们一些 Salamander 的事情
All right. As soon as I can. What have you been doing?
好吧，我尽快。你在做些什么？
I managed to slip out and tell Astrid everything that's happened.
我找机会溜了出去，跟 Astrid 讲了这里所发生的事情
- You might have told me, Jamie!
- There wasn't time.
- 你该告诉我的!  - 没有时间
- She's trying to get Denes away.
- And take him to the Doctor?
- 她在竭力带走 Denes   - 带他去见博士？
- He'd believe Denes.
- Aye, he would.
- 他会相信 Denes 的.   - 是，他会的
How can she get in? Salamander's got guards are everywhere.
那她怎么进来？到处都 Salamander 的警卫
She's got friends here. They're going to arrange passes and the right sort of uniform.
她在这里有朋友。他们会准备通行证和合适的制服
- What sort of uniform?
- I don't know. Messenger delivery or something. Ssh!
- 什么样的制服？  - 我不知道，通讯人员什么的吧。嘘!
I don't know whether Fedorin is to be regarded as a new Controller or not.
我不知道 Fedorin 是否会被推选为(fixme)新的控制员
The burden of office is heavy, my friend.
公务担子很重，我的朋友
They've gone.
他们走了
Astrid and Giles Kent were right.
Salamander IS an evil man.
Astrid 和 Giles Kent 是对的。Salamander 的确是邪恶的人
- I can sense it from all the people here.
- He's bad, all right.
- 我能从这里所有人中感觉到  - 他是坏人，好吧
He's had Denes arrested,
and has Fedorin eating out of his hand.
他把 Denes 抓了，让 Fedorin fixme
- Why do that?
- Replace an honest man with a weaker man,
- 怎么会这样?  - 将一个诚实的人换成一个懦弱的人
but somehow have a hold on him,
and take over the territory.
然后想法抓住他的把柄，就可以夺走版图了
I see - when everything's in a turmoil
because of the earthquakes.
我明白了 - 因为地震，一切都混乱了
And that's lucky to say the least.
说起来这还是幸运的
But you don't really believe that Salamander
could cause earthquakes, do you?
但你不是真的相信 Salamander 能制造地震吧，信吗？
I'm certain Salamander's behind this.
我肯定 Salamander 是幕后黑手
Jamie and Victoria will tell you how bad he is.
Jamie 和 Victoria 会告诉你他有多坏
But why make earthquakes?
但为什么制造地震呢？
Years ago, if a country wanted to invade another,
it threw that country into confusion,
多年以前，如果一个国家打算入侵另外一个，就会让它陷入混乱
making it weak and ripe for take-over.
That's happening here.
削弱它，等机会吞并。这里也是这种情况
You're saying Salamander has found a way
to harness the natural forces of the Earth.
你是说 Salamander 找到了一种方法来利用地球的自然力量
That's difficult to accept.
I'm not saying it's impossible, mind you.
这很难让人接受。但我不是说这是不可能的，注意
You say it's coming from the research station.
Salamander's research station, eh?
你说这来自研究站，Salamander 的研究站，嗯？
That's what I believe, in spite of... Ssh!
我相信是这个，尽管...嘘！
In spite of the fact he invented the sun-store
尽管他发明了日光存储器
and directed conserved energy to areas starved of sun.
把存储的能量转到了日光匮乏的地区
- What made you suspicious?
- The money he was spending.
- 什么让你尝试了怀疑？  - 他花的钱
The materials and food.
It didn't match the requisition orders.
材料和食物。与合理订单的数量不符
- That's valuable evidence.
- New orders appeared.
- 这证据很有价值  - 有新订单出现了
I was made out to be the criminal -
by suggestion, of course.
而我就被安排成了犯罪分子 fixme
I couldn't do it, Salamander. I couldn't do it.
我干不了，Salamander，我干不了这事
I stood there with this man's life in my hands.
我站在那里，手里攥着这个人的性命
This powder - I couldn't use it.
这药粉 - 我下不了手
I gave you the chance
to become something. Somebody.
我给了你机会让你成就点什么，成为一个人物
- You failed to take it.
- There must be some other way.
- 但你没能接住   - 肯定有其它的方法
Of course, my friend. Don't worry.
当然，我的朋友。别担心
- What?  - Don't worry.
- 什么？  - 别担心
You try, you fail - so what?
你努力了，然后失败了 - 那又怎样？
The moon doesn't fall out of the sky!
月亮又不会跑到天外面去！
Come and sit down. Have a drink, huh?
过来坐下。喝一小杯，哈？
Cheer up. We'll find another way.
振作起来。我们想别的办法
I really did try.
我真的尽力试过了
Of course you did.
当然
Don't worry.
别担心
Forget it, huh?
忘了它，哈？
I have an alternative.
我有另一个方法
Your health.
你的健康
I hope you will appreciate this wine.
It's made for me especially in Alaska.
我期望你喜欢这杯酒。这是在 Alaska 特意为我酿造的
One chance, my friend.
只有一次机会，我的朋友
I said one chance!
我说过只有一次机会！
The new man says he's seen someone
in the kitchen gardens.
那个新人说他在厨房花园看见了什么人
Very well. Oh, see to that, will you?
那好。哦，盯着点，行吗？
Suicide, of course. Such a pity.
自杀，当然是。好可惜
- I can't see anything.
- Over there by the trees!
- 我看不到任何东西  - 在那边的树丛里！
He's armed, too. Get down!
他也有枪，趴下！
I'm going out there. Stay down here.
我去那边。蹲在这里
When the rest of the guards come,
send them after me.
其它警卫过来后，让他们跟我来
Astrid's going to get you away.
Astrid 会把你弄走 fixme
An attempt has been made to rescue this man.
Take him to the car.
有人试图救这个人。带他去车里
I'm sorry, Janos.
抱歉，Janos
Stop!
站住！
After them! Arrest that girl!
去追他们！逮捕那个女孩儿！
Well, we all seem to be here,
好了，看来我们都在这里了
except the third member of your escape committee.
除了你那逃跑小队的第三个成员
- What are you talking about?
- You were seen with a girl in the park.
- 你在说什么？  - 有人看见你和一个女孩儿在园区
- The one who tried to escape with Denes.
- We don't even know her.
- 那个女孩儿打算同 Denes 一同逃跑  - 我们都不认识她
A diversion was caused.
fixme
- There was no one outside the kitchen.
- There was, and there was shooting.
- 厨房外面没有谁  - 有，还有人开枪
Three shots have been fired from this gun.
It's yours, isn't it?
这把枪开过三枪。这是你的，对吧？
Pretending to save my life was ingenious,
假装救我的命，这很高明啊
but ingenuity requires a constant stream of new ideas.
但高明就需要后面一系列的新点子
Yours seem to have dried up.
而你似乎已经枯竭了
I come to the Central Zone.
An attempt is made on my life.
我到了中央区，有人试图要我的命fixme
Denes proves to be a traitor.
Denes 到头来是一个叛徒
Fedorin commits suicide because I uncover him.
Fedorin 自杀了，因为我揭露了他
Do your job, Bruce.
You can see they're all in this.
干你的活吧，Bruce。你可以看到他们都在这里面
All right. Take them away.
好吧。把他们带走
Take your hands off me!
把你的手拿开！
I think you should tell me what's going on.
我想你会告诉我这都是怎么回事
One minute you're working with McCrimmon...
前一分钟你与 McCrimmon 挺好
- I thought he saved my life.
- I mean before that. In Kent's office.
- 那是我以为他救了我的命  - 我是说之前，在 Kent 的办公室
- What are you talking about?
- 你在说些什么？
- I saw you there.
- I haven't seen Kent in months.
- 我在那里见到你了  - 我都好几个月没有见过 Kent 了
You were with him, Fariah and the youngsters.
你跟他在一起，还有 Fariah 和这几个年轻人
I thought it was so curious,
I spoke to Benik about it.
我就觉得很奇怪，还同 Benik 谈过此事
- That's the reason I came to this zone.
- But I tell you...
- 这就是我来这个区的原因  - 但我告诉你
I must get back to the research centre.
You will come with me.
我必须回到研究中心去。你得跟我来
It was you.
那就是你
Or someone like you.
或者某个很像你的人